-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 初见 爱喝牛奶 RK翔 Morning 晓笛
校对: 你们茶前辈
明日世界
- 开始了吗?  - 开始了 自我介绍一下吧
- Are we on?  - Yup. Introduce yourself.
嘿 我是弗兰克 你们好吗?
Okay. Hey, I'm Frank. How're you doing?
不用回答 我只是客套一下
Don't answer that. That's rhetorical.
好了 我们直入正题吧
Okay, let's get you up to speed.
这是个关于未来的故事
This is a story about the future.
而这个未来 有点可怕
And the future can be scary.
怎么了?
What?
你真的要用"可怕"这个词吗?
Are you sure you want to go with scary?
- 没错 就是"可怕"  - 好吧
- Yes, I want to go with scary.  - Okay.
好的
Okay.
这个未来 有点可怕
The future can be scary.
政府不稳定
Unstable governments.
人口过剩
Overpopulation.
战争肆虐
Wars on every continent.
饥荒
Famine.
缺水
Water shortages.
环境恶化
Environmental collapse.
还有发达的科技 美妙的景象...
And scientific breakthroughs, wonder and beauty...
你能不要打断吗?
Could you please just stop interrupting?
可以 但你说点积极的吧
I will. Just try to be a little more upbeat.
- 积极的?  - 对 说点你喜欢的
- Upbeat?  - Yeah, tell them what you like.
如果你总打岔 我什么也说不了
I can't tell them anything if you keep interrupting me.
你说得对 抱歉
You're right. Sorry.
我们接着说
As I was saying
随着时间的流逝
with every second that ticks by
- 我们越来越接近...  - 哦 我想到了 你可以跟他们说...
- we get closer and closer...  -  Oh, I know. Tell them about...
不先说明白这些 我没法接着说
I can't tell them anything until I tell them about this.
我们就不能从别的开始说吗?
Can we please just start somewhere else?
好吧 你觉得应该从哪说起?
Fine. Where would you like me to start?
你不老说"未来"曾经不是这个样子的吗?
Well, you keep saying the future wasn't always this way, right?
是的 在我小时候 未来...
It wasn't. When I was a kid, the future was...
- 不是这样的 对吧?  - 嗯
- Different. Right?  - Yeah.
那很好 就从你小时候的未来开始说吧
Okay, cool. Let's start there.
好吧 我小时候
Alright. Well, when I was a kid
未来是另一个样
the future was different.
法拉盛草原可乐娜公园到了!
Flushing Meadows, Corona Park World Fair!
纽约第二大园林公园
带好贵重物品 拥抱未来吧
Don't forget your valuables and enjoy the future.
1964年 纽约世博会
世博会 发明竞赛区
先生 您好
Hello, sir.
- 有什么能帮您的吗?  - 我叫约翰·弗朗西斯·沃克
- May I help you?  - My name is John Francis Walker.
- 我是来赢那五十美元奖金的  - 是么
- I'm here to win $50.  - Is that so.
因为有氮气燃料舱 我就把它拆开带来了
I took it apart because of the nitrogen compartment.
汽车有点颠簸 你知道 亚硝基那么易燃
Seeing as how the bus ride was kinda bumpy, and, you know nitro.
其实我也可以用过氧化氢做燃料
I could have used a hydrogen peroxide-powered engine,
然后通过火箭背带解除连接
while lapses of that with their rocket belt,
但我想在可行性和耐力上
and I guess there were some issues
还是存在一些问题的
with maneuverability and flight duration and stuff.
这是喷气背包
It's a jet pack.
看出来了吧
Obviously.
你自己做的吗?
You made this yourself?
雅典娜 你怎么来了?
Athena, what are you doing here?
是 还是不是?
Did you? Or didn't you?
额 我...
Uh. I...
- 什么意思?  - 这是你自己做的吗?
- What?  - Did you make this yourself?
是的
Yeah.
为什么?
Why?
我想 我厌倦了等别人来替我做这些事情了
I guess I got tired of waiting around for someone else to do it for me.
它能用吗?
Does it work?
额... 当然
Um... sure. Yeah.
大多数情况下
Mostly.
只是从技术角度来说 它不是...
It just doesn't really, you know, technically...
在飞
fly.
如果从技术上说它能飞的话
But if it did, you know, technically fly,
这东西有什么用处?
what would it's purpose be?
你的喷气背包如何能让世界变得更好?
How would your jet pack make the world a better place?
增添了乐趣 不行吗?
Can't it just be fun?
沃克先生 不要告诉我你只知道乐趣
Mr. Walker, please tell me you can do better than 'fun'.
它让一切皆有可能
Anything is possible.
我不懂这什么意思
I don't know what that means.
如果我走在街上 看到一个孩子背着喷气背包飞过
If I was walking down the street and I saw some kid with a jet pack fly over me,
我会相信一切皆有可能
I'd believe anything's possible.
我会被激励
I'd be inspired.
这算不算让世界变得更好?
Doesn't that make the world a better place?
算是吧
I suppose it would.
前提是它好用
If, it worked.
但不幸的是 它不好用
Unfortunately, it does not.
如果它不好用 那一切都白搭
And if it doesn't work, it has no purpose at all.
谢谢你能来 沃克先生
Thank you for your time, Mr. Walker.
我能让它好用
But I can make it work.
精神可嘉啊
That's the spirit.
在那之前 好好玩吧...
Until then, young man...
年轻人
have fun.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
我挺喜欢他
I like him.
雅典娜 不行
Athena, no.
发明创造大厅
你凭什么觉得这玩意能飞?
What makes you think you're gonna make this thing fly?
- 我是个乐天派  - 你在浪费时间
- I'm optimistic.  - You're wasting your time.
- 不是  - 乱七八糟
- I'm not.  - Damn contraption.
才不是乱七八糟!
It's not a contraption!
根本不能飞
It doesn't work.
- 我会让它飞起来的  - 不 你不能
- I can make it work.  - No, you can't.
我绝不会放弃的
I'm not giving up.
别转过来 装作没事
Don't turn around. Be cool.
我不是说别转过来吗?
What did I just tell you?
- 抱歉  - 别说话
- Sorry.  - Stop talking.
看那边 五点钟方向
Look over there, 5 o'clock.
你不知道钟表吗?
You know? On a clock?
五点在哪?
Where the 5 is?
是那边
That way.
我先过去找他们 你数到二十再过来
I'm going with them. You count to 20 then follow us.
别被发现了
Don't get spotted.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是未来 弗兰克·沃克
I'm the future, Frank Walker.
借过一下
Excuse me.
不好意思
Sorry.
喔 喔 喔... 抱歉
Whoa whoa whoa... sorry folks,
你们得等下条船了
you're gonna have to wait for the next boat.
下条船马上就到
There'll be another boat in just a minute.
有人吗?
Hello?
下午好 请登上传输舱
Good afternoon. Please step aboard the transport.
舱位已就绪
The site is active.
请戴上防护头盔
Please put on your head protection,
以避免重大创伤
in order to prevent significant injury.
创伤?
Injury?
传输十秒钟后开始
Transport will commence in 10 seconds.
等一下
Wait.
- 等一下  - 五
- Wait. Wait  - 5.
四
4.
三
3.
二
2.
一
1.
切勿进入
嘿 那是我的
Hey, that's mine.
你把它修好了?
Did you just fix it?
等一下
Wait.
嘿!
Hey!
啊!
Aww!
哇
Whoa.
哇!
Wooo!
嘿
Hey.
- 现在能飞了  - 不
- It works now.  - No
但这是哪呢?
So. What is this place?
然后一切急转直下
And then, everything went to hell.
- 哦 天啊  - 没错
- Oh, boy.  - Well it did.
所以你可以跟他们讲蓝天 喷气背包...
So you gave them like, one second of blue skies and jet packs and....
他们应该知道其中的风险
It's important they need to know the stakes.
我想他们能够发现 所剩时间有限
I think they can figure out clocks counting down on them.
- 要不你来讲吧?  - 不 还是你讲吧
- Do you want to tell the story?  - No, you're gonna...
如果你觉得讲得比我好
Because if you think you can tell the story better
我很乐意一边听着
I would absolutely love to hear you try.
- 哦 真的吗?  - 当然是真的
- Wow, really?  - Really.
也许我比你更够格
Well, I guess technically I am more qualified.
是么? 为什么?
Are you? How so?
因为我不像你 我是个乐天派
Because unlike you, I'm an optimist.
- 嘿 宝贝 你开始拍了吗?  - 是录像
- Hey. Babe, you filming?  - It's video.
我知道
I knew it.
- 你在录像  - 好的 继续录 宝贝
- You video it.  - Okay, go ahead, sweetie.
开始吧 凯西
Do your thing, Casey.
那是天狼星
That's Sirius.
那是老人星
That's Canopus.
那是大角星
That's Acturus.
半人马座
Rigel Centaurus.
织女星 小犬座 御夫座 猎户座
Vega, Procyon, Capella, Betelgeuse.
你为什么这么喜欢星星 凯西?
Why do you love the stars so much, Casey?
因为我想去星星上面
Because, I wanna go there.
但那太远了
But it's so far away.
需要很长时间才能到 非常长
It will take a long time. A real long time.
如果你好不容易到了 却发现那里什么也没有 怎么办?
What if you get all the way up there and there's nothing?
也可能什么都有
What if there's everything.
- 天啊  - 怎么了?
- Oh, boy.  - What?
你打算把你的童年回忆一遍?
We're gonna go through your entire childhood?
你也是从小时候说起的 我只是想说一下背景
You started when you were a kid. I'm just giving them context.
快说正题 好吧? 时间有限
Just move it along, okay? They don't have all day.
好的 没问题
Cool. You got it.
美国航天局发射站旧址
你是谁
Identify yourself.
内特 别把老爸吵醒了 否则我跟你没完
Nate, if you wake up dad, I will crush you.
你不该偷溜出去
You shouldn't sneak out.
你还不该盖着婴儿毯呢
Well you shouldn't still need a lovey.
爸爸说我可以盖的
Dad says it's okay to sleep with.
那是因为他不希望你长大
That's because he doesn't want you to grow up.
你又去发射站了吗?
Were you at the platform again?
你去那里做什么?
What do you do out there?
你在设法阻止他们? 不让他们拆了那里?
Are you trying to stop them? From taking it down?
不 那样就犯法了
No. That would make me a criminal
而且不是小孩子们的好榜样 特别是对于你
and a pretty terrible role model to impressionable youth such as yourself.
但如果有人这么做了
But if someone else did it
我想
I've to assume,
他们会相信
they believed,
即使是小孩子们的行为
even the teeniest of actions
也可以改变未来
could change the future.
你怎么那么肯定?
How can you be sure?
因为我懂得多
Because I know how things work.
他们为什么要拆发射站?
Why are they taking the platform down?
因为很多事做起来难 放弃却很容易
Guess it's hard to have ideas, and easy to give up.
但你不会放弃的
But you won't,
对吧?
right?
永不放弃
Never.
DNA扫描
嘿 爸 我去上学了
Hey, dad. Heading to school.
- 你的午饭  - 嘿
- Made you lunch.  - Hey.
别忘拿了
Wrap it up.
- 你怎么...  - 你可以的
- How'd you do...  - You would've gotten it.
你好 我是埃迪·纽顿
Yeah, Eddie Newton.
什么?
What?
三台吊车都坏了?
All three cranes.
知道了 道格拉斯
Alright, Douglas.
谢谢打电话来 再见
Thanks for the call. Bye.
出什么事了?
Everything okay?
卡纳维拉尔那的设备又出问题了
Yeah, the equipment over at Canaveral's down again.
- 奇怪  - 确实奇怪
- Weird.  - Really weird.
好消息是你可以休息一天了
Well at least you get the day off.
他们正在从奥兰多运来备用吊车
Actually, their bringing in replacement cranes from Orlando
所以我中午就能去工作
so I will be back to work by noon.
- 很棒  - 凯西
- That's fantastic. - Case.
怎么了?
Yeah?
他们肯定会拆掉发射站的
Nothing's gonna stop 'em from taking down that platform.
肯定会 而且如果拆完了 我就失业了
Nothing. And when we're done, I'm out of a job.
谁也无法阻止这件事的发生
There's nothing anyone can do about it.
- 不可避免  - 你会找到新工作的
- It's inevitable.  - Well then, you'll find something else.
你可是宇航局的工程师
You're a NASA engineer.
但发射站都要拆了
With nothing to launch.
- 两只狼的故事  - 别说了
- There are two wolves.  - Case.
你总是给我讲这个故事 现在我要给你讲讲
You've told me this story my entire life and now I'm telling you.
有两只狼 他们总是打架
There are two wolves, and they're always fighting.
一只是阴暗和绝望
One, is darkness and despair.
一只是光明和希望
The other is light and hope.
哪只狼会赢?
Which wolf wins?
别这样 凯西
Come on, Case.
好吧 那就别回答
Okay. Fine. Don't answer.
你养的那只会赢
Whichever one you feed.
很好
Good.
吃掉它 走吧
Eat. Come on.
确保同归于尽计划
Mutually assured destruction.
如今 储核国家或者恐怖组织
Today, any nuclear country or terrorist
完全有能力造成大片区域的毁灭
is capable of inflicting damage on a massive scale.
- 用武器...  - 环境熵
- With weapons of...  - Environmental entropy.
融化的冰川不会等我们弄明白全球变暖是否是真的
The polar ice caps aren't waiting for us to decide if climate change is real.
持续上升的海平面 急剧变化的气候
Rising coastal waters, intensifying weather patterns
这些是我们走向未来过程中...
they're all punching, our one way ticket to...
反乌托邦是指不理想社会
Dystopia, by definition, not perfect.
赫胥黎（生物学家） '美丽新世界'
Huxley's 'Brave new world'.
柏来勃利的'华氏451度'
Bradbury's 'Fahrenheit 451'.
奥威尔的'1984'
Orwell's '1984'.
曾被认为是虚构的未来派小说中的情节 已经变成现实
Once considered fiction, these futuristic novels are actually happening right now.
而且似乎更糟糕 纽顿小姐?
And they seem to be getting worse. Yes, Miss Newton?
我们怎样挽回?
Can we fix it?
什么?
Sorry?
我知道情况很糟 我们怎样挽回呢?
I get things are bad, but what are we doing to fix it?
周末愉快 各位同学
Have a good weekend, everybody.
纽顿?
Newton?
- 是的  - 你被保释了
- Yeah.  - You made bail.
摩托车被没收 你的其他物品在那边
Motorcycle's in impound. You can pick up your personal effects over there.
- 纽顿?  - 是的
- Newton?  - Yeah.
好了
Alright. Okay.
一个钱夹 47.32美元现金
One money clip, $47.32
一张加州的驾照 一顶棒球帽
One Florida state driver's license, one baseball cap.
还有... 一个勋章 一包比曼口香糖
We got... one pin, one pack of Beemans gum.
还有这个不知道是什么
And I don't know what this is.
在这签字
Sign here.
- 这个不是我的  - 什么不是你的?
- That's not mine.  - What's not yours?
勋章
The pin.
我没有...
I've never...
啊! 怎么回事!
Aw! What! What!
不会吧
No way.
我刚才一直在这里吗?
Have I been here the whole time?
我知道
I know.
别动!
No!
我自己捡
I got it.
你不知道我费了多少口舌才让国土安全部放弃指控你 凯西
You have no idea of the strings I had to pull to keep Homeland Security from pressing charges, Casey.
这不只是破坏公共财产 好吗?
This is not just vandalism, alright?
那是宇航局 是政府的资产
It's NASA. It's government property.
你见过这东西吗?
Have you ever seen this before?
你怎么没听进去呢?
You're not getting it, are you?
我对你很生气
I'm very upset with you.
我明白 你非常生气
I get it. You're angry, I understand.
你看一眼好吗 这东西看起来奇怪吗?
But I just need you to look at it. Does it look weird?
别碰它!
Don't touch it!
你大呼小叫的干嘛?
Why are you yelling at me?
老爸 开车时不要碰 太危险了
Not while you're driving, Dad. It's dangerous.
快靠边停
Just pull over.
停车
Pull over.
我发誓 凯西 你要是敢嗑药...
I swear to God, Case, if you're on drugs...
我才没有嗑药 听着
I'm not on drugs. Just, look.
现在我要你像一个酷酷的
I need you to be NASA dad now.
眼观超前的航天局老爸 好吗?
New frontier dad, okay?
一旦你接触到这个勋章 所有事情就不言而喻了
All will be explained, as soon as you touch this pin.
什么 这...
What, it's...
没有反应?
It's not working?
你什么都看不见!
You're not seeing this!
你够了!
Stop it!
老实说 凯西 我不知道你是中了什么邪
Honestly, Casey. I don't know what's gotten into you.
- 拉我一把 伙计们  - 动作不行啊 德克斯特
- Come on, guys.  - Bad move, Dexter.
真是吓尿了
Totally sweat.
走吧 逗逼们
Come on, idiots.
我们要赶不上参加研发了
We're gonna be late for R&D.
悬浮列车还有一分钟到站
The hover rail will be arriving in 1 minute.
你要上来吗?
Are you coming?
- 你看得见我?  - 抓紧时间吧
- You can see me?  - We don't have all day.
- 等等我们!  - 北上线 列车开始启动
- Wait for us!  - North bound line. Now departing.
下一站 航天港
Next stop: Space port.
爸爸 你别为难我了
Dad, you're embarrassing me.
难道你能做到每天都传送吗?
Do you promise you'll transmit everyday?
- 甚至当你在覆盖范围外  - 拜托 这又不是什么大事
- Even when you're out of range.  - Come on, what's the big deal.
我们只不过出门二十光年远而已
We're only going twenty light years out.
航天港到了
Now arriving: space port.
- 伙计们 快过来  - 来了
- Hey guys, over here.  - Oh, hey.
快来 我们特意给你留了位置
Come on. We saved a seat, just for you.
挑这时候没电?
Now you run out of power?
- 内特 爬起来  - 不是我做的!
- Nate, wake up.  - I didn't do it!
老爸把电脑密码改了 你知道新密码吗?
Dad changed the password to his computer. Do you know it?
你闻起来像刚从沼泽地里爬出来一样
You smell like swamp.
只要告诉我密码 你就可以好好回去睡觉了
Tell me the password and you can go back to sleep.
你可以用手机上网啊
Your phone has internet.
我的手机掉水里泡坏了
My phone got soaked in a lagoon.
那好吧
Fine.
我们到底在搜索什么?
What are we looking for?
停! 找的就是就是它
Stop! That's it.
极为稀有并具收藏价值的一九六四年世界博览会纪念勋章
Extremely rare collectible pin commemorating the 1964 World's Fair.
是全球太空时代专家及商人最佳的收藏选择
Experts and purveyors of the most extensive selection of space-age collectibles in the World.
这个网站看起来很老旧
Whoa. This site is like ancient.
把他们的电话给我
Okay, give me their number.
他们没有电话
They don't have a number.
没有电话?
They don't have a number?
不过有个地址
They have an address.
好了 听着 你要告诉老爸 说你醒来的时候看见我正离开...
Okay, look. You are gonna tell Dad, you woke up, saw me leaving...
我和你说我要和朋友们去露营 明天会打电话回来
I told you I was going camping with friends and I will call tomorrow.
- 能帮我这个忙吗?  - 除非你告诉我实情
- Can you do that for me?  - Only if you tell me what's going on.
我... 我...
I... I...
我觉得我看见了...
I think that I saw...
也就是我到过未来...
That I went to...
未来
the future.
我也能去吗?
Can I come, too?
暂时... 还不行
Not... yet.
你好 请问凯西·纽顿在家吗?
Hello. Is Casey Newton home?
不在
Uh. No.
她订了些曲奇饼 我是来送货的
She ordered some cookies and I'm delivering them.
你是女童子军吗?
You're a girl scout?
当然了
Of course, I am.
那你为什么没有穿制服?
Why aren't you wearing a uniform?
衣服拿去洗了
It's at the cleaners.
可你拿的明明是奥利奥
Those are Oreos.
你能告诉我凯西什么时候会回来吗?
Could you please tell me when Casey will be back?
她和朋友去露营了 要在外面待好几天
She went camping with some friends. She's gonna be gone for a couple of days.
你就是这样告诉你父母的吧?
Is that what you told your parents?
是的...
Um... Yeah.
可这并不是实话
But it's not true.
是实话
Yeah, it is.
不 内森 不是实话
No, Nathan. It's not.
不要问我怎么知道你的名字
Don't ask me how I knew your name.
我同样知道你在对我说谎
I know it the same way I know that you're lying to me.
你是从未来来的吗?
Are you from the future?
你猜的很准嘛
You clearly understand.
所以 为什么不告诉我实情?
So why aren't you telling me what I need to know?
那枚勋章
That pin thing,
失效了 所以她想去再找一枚
it stopped working. She went to find another one.
内森 她去哪儿了?
Nathan, where is she looking?
有人在吗?
Hello?
这周打折
Sale this week.
前面三排的东西全部三折
Front 3 shelves, 70% off.
不 谢了 我不是来买东西的
Oh. No thanks, I'm not here to buy anything.
我是想打听这东西的信息
I was hoping that you could tell me about this.
雨果!
Hugo!
欢迎光临 从过去的冲击...
Welcome, to blast from the Past...
多谢你的帮忙 亲爱的
Thank you for the help, dear.
如果你不关门的话根本就不需要我多此一举
Well. If you'd just kept it open you wouldn't need my help.
不关门的话就会破坏哥帅气的出场效果
If I kept it open it would ruin the effect which is everything.
原谅我老婆 她就是不懂欣赏 我是雨果·卡恩兹巴克
Pardon my wife, she has no respect for showmanship. Hugo Gernsback.
- 你需要什么?  - 她有枚勋章
- How may I help you?  - She has a pin.
她有枚勋章
She has a pin.
我看见你在网路上寻找这东西...
I saw that you were looking for one online...
你是从哪儿得到这东西的?
Where did you get it?
你能告诉我这勋章的信息吗?
What can you tell me about it?
你得告诉我这枚勋章是谁给你的 我才能告诉你勋章的信息
I can't tell you anything about it unless you tell me who gave it to you.
我才不要先开口
I'm not going first.
那好吧 我们没得谈了
Well it seems our business here is done.
看起来确实如此
Seems it is.
当你触碰到它的时候
Saw something, didn't you.
你看到了不一样的东西 对吗?
When you touched it.
看见了不可思议的场景?
Something incredible?
那是真的吗?
It's real?
当然是真的了
Of course it is.
别问我为什么我们想也不敢想的高科技已经被这些人开放出来了
Don't ask me how these people have developed technologies we haven't even dreamed of yet.
等等 什么这些人?
Wait. What people?
你有没有想象过
Have you ever wondered what would happen
当所有天才 艺术家 科学家汇聚一堂的时候 会发生什么...
if all the geniuses, the artists, the scientists, the...
世界上最聪明 最富有创造力的人...
smartest, most creative people in the world...
决心改变世界?
decided to actually change it?
可是要在哪儿?
But where?
在哪儿他们才能做这事儿呢?
Where could they even do such a thing?
他们需要一个没有政治 没有官僚主义 没有干扰
They'd need a place free from politics, bureaucracy, distractions,
没有贪念的地方
greed.
一个神秘的地方
A secret place.
在那里 他们可以尽情的发挥自己的想象
Where they could build whatever they were crazy enough to imagine.
他们称自己为"至高点"
'Plus Ultra', they called themselves.
然而唯一能看见这个地方的方法 只有通过接触这些勋章
The only way to see it, however, is through contact with one of these.
他们制造这些勋章干嘛? 想用来做什么?
Why did they make them? What are they for?
有流言说...
Rumor has it...
他们想要把这个秘密公之于众
They were about to go public.
和全世界一起分享这个成果
Share what they had built with the whole world.
可不幸的是...
Unfortunately...
没能成功
That never happened.
为什么没能成功?
Why not?
我想我已经说了够多了 小姑娘 我...
I think we've shared enough, young lady. I...
看在我对你坦诚相待的份上...
As, we've decided to trust you...
也相信我吧 告诉我
Please, trust us. And tell me,
你从哪儿拿到这东西的?
where did you get it?
我不知道
I don't know.
亲爱的 不知道是几个意思?
What do you mean, honey?
我从牢里出来就发现它夹杂在我的物品里
I kinda got arrested and it was in with my stuff.
在你的物品里?
In with your stuff?
是的 我都不知道它是怎么冒出来的
Yeah, I don't know how it got there.
那是什么?
What was that?
能否告诉我们是谁给你的?
Tell us who gave it to you, please?
没人给我!
No one gave it to me!
亲爱的 骗鬼呢
It's very unlikely, sweetheart.
这样的话
Uh. You know what?
我想我还是走吧
I think I'm gonna go now.
谢谢你们的帮助
Thanks for your help.
我出一千美元 只要你告诉我谁这枚勋章是谁给你的
A $1000 if you tell me where you acquired the pin.
我不知道
I don't know.
- 那一万美元  - 是一个女孩吗? 一个小女孩吗?
- 10,000.  - Was it a girl? A little girl?
我听不懂你们在说什么
I don't know what you guys are talking about.
希望你们今天过得操蛋的开心
Have a nice day, enjoy your freakout!
告诉我们她在哪里 说出来我们就放你走
Tell us where she is and you will be spared.
这是在开玩笑吗?
This is a joke, right?
那个女孩在哪儿?
Where's the girl?
我不知道 不知道
I... I don't. I don't know.
我会让你开口的
You will tell us about the girl.
我不知道什么女孩 我已经说过了 我... 我不...
I don't know any girl. I told you, I... I don't...
那个女孩在哪?
Where is the girl?
我不知道什么女孩!
I don't know any girl!
我们得走了
We have to go.
快点 趁现在!
Come on. Now!
这是一个时间炸弹 可以让时间停滞 可是维持不了多久
This is a time bomb. Stops time, but not for long.
- 什么?  - 听我说
- What?  - Listen to me.
球体正在坍塌 而你正对着枪口
The sphere's collapsing and you're in the line of fire.
我们得走了 不然你会死的
We need to go, or you will die.
我被卡住了
I'm stuck.
被卡住了!
I'm stuck!
这只是暂时的 拉住我的手
But only temporarily. Take my hand.
一旦你自由了 我就马上拉开你
The moment you're free I'll pull you clear.
记得站在我身后
And stay behind me.
准备好没?
Ready?
是那个女孩!
The girl!
小心!
Look out!
我们得走了
We have to go.
他们马上就要自毁了 我们得立刻撤离!
They're about to self-destruct. We have to go now!
我一定是在做梦 一定是在做梦
Crazy enough to imagine. Crazy enough to imagine.
凯西 快上来 他们马上就要来了
Casey, get up. They'll be coming.
- 什么?  - 走!
- What?  - Go!
- 我知道  - 我不知道我...
- I know  - I don't know what I...
- 进去 凯西  - 不能上车
- Get in, Casey.  - can't get in the car.
你怎么知道我的名字
How do you know my name?
上车就是了
Just get in the car.
刚刚发生了什么?
What just happened?
两个AA想要杀死你
2 AA units targeted you for extermination.
我救了你 然后他们自毁了
I saved your life, they self-destructed.
等等 什么是AA?
Wait. AAs?
人形电子
Audio Animatronics.
他们是机器人?
They were robots?
不 比机器人还要先进并且还要...
No, advanced and more...
好吧 好吧 他们机器人
Sure. Okay, Robots.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我的名字叫雅典娜
My name is Athena.
你的勋章就是我给你的
I'm the one who gave you the pin.
勋章? 那个... 哦 勋章!
The pin? The... Whoa, the-the pin!
是的
Yeah.
可惜当时没等我告诉你
And I do wish you hadn't run off
其他关于勋章的必要信息 你就跑了
before I had a chance to give you some rather necessary contexts.
信息? 你在说什么?
Contexts? What are you even talking about?
你这么小怎么能开车的!
How are you driving a car!
你到底是谁?
Who are you?
我是一名招募员...
I'm a recruiter...
招... 我... 知道... 招...募...员...
re...  I... know... re re...cruiter...
六十秒自我修复
60 seconds to self-destruct.
我的翻译器受损了(日语)
My translator is damage. (Japanese)
抱歉
So sorry about that.
你是... 他们中的一员
You're... one of them.
当然了
Obviously.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
停下 我是来帮助你的!
Stop, I'm trying to help you!
上帝啊! 上帝啊！
Oh my god. Oh my god!
这不是真的 这不是真的
This isn't happening. This isn't happening.
不是吧!
No, way!
让我下车!
Let me out of this car!
- 别叫了! 不可能  - 不!
- Stop yelling! I will not. - No!
- 让我下车!  - 别做梦了!
- Let me out now! - I will not!
菇凉 我都把最后一枚勋章给你了
I gave you my very last pin, young lady.
我不能白白浪费它
And I am not about to let it go to waste.
最后一枚勋章是什么意思?
What do you mean your last pin?
我看见的那个地方
The place I saw.
- 是真实存在的?  - 毋庸置疑
- It exists?  - Of course, it does.
可是如果你不跟着我
But if you don't come with me,
它将会不复存在
it won't for much longer.
为什么?
Why not?
因为他们建造了本来不应该建造的东西
Because they built something they shouldn't have.
那是什么?
Wha... Built what?
你是准备把时间花在不停的发问上 等着别人来干掉我们吗?
Do you want to keep asking me questions until someone arrives to murder us?
才不是
No.
那你是要选哪条路?
Then which way do you want to go?
往回走...
Backwards...
还是前进?
Or forwards?
你能带我到那里去吗?
And you could take me there?
可以
I can.
我来开车
I'm driving.
你们可以解散了 谢谢
You fellas are released. Thanks.
好了 伙计们
Alrighty, boys.
消防队长说安全了 我们可以进去调查了
Fire chief says we're cleared to go in and poke around.
希望店铺爆炸的时候 店员都出去吃午餐了
Hopefully, they were out for lunch and nobody was in there once she went boom.
队长
Captain.
下午好 先生 我是特勤处的大卫·克拉克
Afternoon, sir. Dave Clark, Secret Service.
看起来你们做的不错嘛
Looks like you got yourself a doosy here.
特勤处?
Secret Service?
他们是要去哪里?
Hey, where are they going?
他们是在保护场地
They're securing the premises.
谢谢你们的帮忙 不过接下来的事由我们接手
Thanks so much for your help, but we're going to take it from here.
戴尔 我在窗外找到了这东西
Hey Dale, found this just outside the window.
你有见过这东西吗?
Ever seen anything like it?
只是什么鬼?
What the hell?
上帝啊!
God almighty!
打折~\(≧▽≦)/~啦啦啦 这周 七折 是一个女孩? 是一个小女孩吗?
Sale. This week, 70%. Was it a girl? A little girl?
是一个女孩? 是一个小女孩吗? 是一个女孩? 是一个小女孩吗?
Was it a girl? A little girl? Was it a girl? A little girl?
你愿意告诉我这里发生了什么吗 年轻人?
You wanna tell me what's going on here, son?
当然 不愿意
No, sir. I do not.
是一个女孩? 是一个小女孩吗?
Was it a girl? A little girl?
呼叫总督尼克斯
Contact Governor Nix.
告诉他我们找到小女孩了
Tell him we found the girl.
左转!
Veer left!
拜托下次早点提个醒
A little more of a heads-up next time.
要不这样吧 你直接告诉我咱们要去哪儿好了
Hey, here's an idea. Why don't you just tell me where we're going.
纽约的皮茨菲尔德
Pittsfield of New York.
我们去那儿干嘛?
What's in Pittsfield, New York?
去找能带我们回去的人
Someone who can get us back in.
等等 你说你把最后一枚勋章给我了
Hold on, you said that you gave me your last pin.
你到底一共给过多少人?
How many other people did you give them to?
这不重要
Not important.
我甚至不是你第一选择
I'm not even your first choice.
我一个月前才找到你
I only found you a month ago
你那时候蓄意破坏政府财产
when you started wantingly destroying government property.
这行为刚好和我招募的搜寻参数相吻合
Which happens to go on my search parameters for recruitment.
更别提 你可是在弗曼·多伯特测试得了73分啊
Not to mention you scored a 73 on the Feynman Daubert scale.
73分?
73?
这算高分吗?
Is that good?
等等 等等 招募我去干嘛
Wait. Hold-Hold on. Recruitment for what?
我被禁止回答这个问题
I'm not allowed to answer that.
谁禁止你?
Who's not allowing you?
我警告你 我被禁止回答这些问题
I'm not allowed to answer that and I should warn you.
你要是再问我问题 我只能采取相应的防范措施了
You keep asking me questions and my countermeasure protocol will initiate.
什么防范措施?
Okay, and what does that mean?
我会关机
I will shut down.
你才不会
You will not.
你敢试就行
Try me.
你说 他们在那边造了不应该造的东西
You said that they built something they shouldn't have.
那边出了什么事吗? 某些不好的事情?
Did something happen over there? Something bad?
我操...!
Son of a b...!
别接起来 千万别接电话
Please don't answer. Please don't answer.
喂 这是埃迪·纽顿的手机
Hey. You've reached Eddie Newton's cellphone.
请留言 我会打给你的
Leave me a message and I will call you back.
嗨 老爸 是我凯西 嗯
Hey Dad, it's Casey. Um.
我让内特跟你说 我在野营 其实我没有
I told Nate to tell you that I was camping, but I'm not camping.
我不想欺骗你
I just don't like lying to you.
但我不知道怎么老实跟你说 因为...
But I didn't know how to tell you the truth because...
我遇到了一件非比寻常的事...
But something highly unusual is happening, and...
好吧 我的意思就是
Okay, my point is,
我没事 而且我会一直没事的
I'm fine. I will continue to be fine.
我没在吸毒 我也没加入什么邪教
I'm not on drugs. I haven't joined a cult.
我会马上回来的
I won't be gone long.
我过几天再打给你
And I will call again soon.
我爱你 老爸
I love you, Dad.
哦! 我的天啊!
OH! Oh my god!
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
好 非常好 谢谢
Yes. Fine, thank you.
我还以为我弄坏你了
I thought I broke you or something.
应该换我来开了
I should drive.
凯西
Casey.
我知道你没理由相信我
I know you have no reason to trust me.
但为了寻找像你这样的人 我已经找了很久了
But I've been looking for someone like you for a very long time.
所以求你了
Now please.
停下来
Pull over.
你可以把勋章给这么多人...
Of all the people you could give one of those pins to...
为什么给我?
Why me?
因为你很特别
Because you're special.
哦 是吗
Oh yeah.
- 我算特别吗  - 是真的!
- I'm special.  - You are!
说说我们要去见的人
So this guy we're gonna go see.
他叫什么名字?
What's his name?
他叫弗兰克
His name is Frank.
弗兰克·沃克
Frank Walker.
他也很特别
He's special, too.
弗兰克·沃克
Frank Walker.
嗨! 等等! 你要去哪里!
Hey! Wait! Where are you going!
现在好了
Just great.
沃克家
你的爪印去哪里了?
Where are your paw prints?
这太酷了
That is cool.
我能听到你 你知道吧
I can hear you, you know.
走开
Go away.
你没看到有狗吗?
Didn't you see the dog?
看到了
Yeah!
是全息图像 大白天你怎么做到的?
It's a hologram. How did you do that in daylight?
- 很厉害啊  - 你是谁?
- Pretty impressive.  - Who are you?
你想干嘛?
What do you want?
你叫弗兰克·沃克 对吧?
You're Frank Walker, right?
我叫凯西 我要你带我去那里
My name's Casey. And I want you to take me there.
带你...
Take you...
哪里?
where?
我碰到这东西后看到的地方
To the place I saw when I touched this.
你哪里拿到的?
Where did you get this?
从小女孩 叫雅典娜
A little girl. Athena.
她在哪里?
Where is she?
她把我抛在这里了...
She ditched me here...
她当然这么做了 听着
Of course, she did. Look.
不管你从哪里来 小鬼 回家去
Wherever you came from, kid, go back.
不 我要你带我去那里
No, I want you to take me there.
- 我看到了...  - 你所看到的 已经不存在了
- What I saw...  - What you saw, is gone.
你寻找的这东西 它已经不存在了
This, what you're looking for, it doesn't exist anymore.
不 我的直觉告诉我 我必须去那里
No, I feel... I feel like, like I have to go.
那里是我应该去的地方
Like, I'm supposed to go.
为什么?
Why?
因为他们在火箭里给你留了个位置?
Because they're saving a seat on a rocket ship just for you?
你看到的是几十年前录下的一段广告
What you saw was a commercial that was recorded decades ago.
是未能发出的邀请 因为聚会被取消了
It was an invitation that never went out, because the damn party got canceled.
你不用做任何事情
You are not supposed to do anything.
你被洗脑了 以为自己应该去参加什么大事件
You've been manipulated to feel like you're part of something incredible.
就好像你是很特殊一样
Like you were special.
但你不是
But you weren't.
你什么都不是
You're not.
所以是不同意咯?
So that's a no?
我操...
Son of a b...
哦 你个小...
Oh, you little...
你知道吗 我可以马上报警
You know. I could call the cops anytime!
马上!
Anytime!
你必须... 我只给我5秒钟!
You have... I'm giving you 5 seconds!
我不会走的!
I'm not leaving!
你要么告诉我怎么去哪里 要么杀了我!
Either tell me how to get there, or kill me!
如果你碰里面任何东西 不用说我也直接动手!
If you touch anything in there, that's exactly what I'll do!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我就随便乱摸了!
I'm touching things!
马上给我开门!
Open this door, now!
我说真的 我要把你臭揍一顿
I'm serious. I'll knock you out.
这个像伸缩长号一样的东西是什么
Hey what's this doohickey with a trombone slidey thing?
别乱动! 我说真的!
Leave that alone! I'm serious!
那你会带我去那里吗?
Will you take me there?
- 不会!  - 那你哪里认真了!
- No!  - Then you're not serious!
拜托 你不觉得这个有趣吗?
Oh come on. You didn't think that was funny?
你是在录像吗?
You're recording this?
如果我能让你笑 我想...
If I get you to laugh, I wanna, you know,
记录下来以后再看
have it for posterity.
我笑过了
I laughed.
你是微笑 微笑不是一种笑
You smiled. A smile's not a laugh.
所有人都会笑 这是生物的一种需求
Everyone laughs. It's a biological need.
实际上你错了 睡觉才是生物的一种需求
Actually it isn't. Sleep is a biological need.
我也从来没见过你睡觉
And I've never seen you sleep, either.
不管迟早 我总会让你笑的
Well, sooner or later I'm gonna make you laugh.
直到你笑出来 我是不会放弃的
Until you do, I'm not gonna stop trying.
也许你应该放弃
Maybe you should.
什么?
What?
别再试了
Stop trying.
为什么?
Why?
你一定要录下来吗?
Must you record this?
- 出去!  - 等一下
- Get out!  - Wait a second.
这是... 这是什么? 是倒计时吗?
What is... What is that? Is that a countdown?
我不会走的 我应该要知道这里的情况
I am not leaving. I deserve to know what's going on around here.
- 你应该?  - 对的 我应该要知道些答案
- You deserve?  - Yeah, I deserve some answers.
- 什么答案?  - 我知道你曾经在那里
- Answers to what?  - I know that you were there.
你什么都不懂
You don't know anything.
你怎么能离开那地方?
How can you ever leave a place like that?
因为他们赶我走的!
Because they threw me out!
他们赶我走的 然后他们把所有通道都锁上了
They threw me out and they locked every door back in.
是因为你造了一个你不应该造的东西?
Was it because you built that something that you shouldn't have?
谁告诉你的?
Who told you that?
就是这个? 那个东西?
Is that it? The something?
如果我能准确地告诉你...
If I could tell you the date...
你死的日期...
The exact date that you're gonna die...
- 你愿意知道吗?  - 你怎么知道的?
- Would you wanna know?  - How would you know?
- 假设我就知道了  - 怎么 你是通灵的?
- Let's just say I did.  - What, are you psychic?
- 不是 但这不是重点  - 那你是怎么知道的呢?
- No, that's not the point.  - Then what is your basis for knowing this.
假设上来说 好吧 就... 就
Hypothetical. Alright, just... just use your imagination. Alright?
- 好的  - 好吧
- Alright.  - Okay.
就假设前提是有这么一个宇宙 我完全肯定地知道
Just accept that there's a world where I know with absolute certainty,
你的死亡日期
the exact time of your death.
那现在
Now.
你想让我告诉你吗?
You want me to tell you or not?
当然想啦 谁不想呢?
Of course, I would. Who wouldn't?
但...
But.
如果...
What if...
知道我的死期是导致我死亡的原因...
Accepting my death is what causes it...
答案还是"想知道"
so the answer is "Yes".
我想要你告诉我
I would want you to tell me,
- 但我不会相信你  - 你不得不相信我
- But I wouldn't believe you.  - You have to believe me.
为什么? 不是说 自己的路自己决定吗?
Why? Don't we like, make our own destiny and stuff?
怎么了?
What?
小鬼 你是谁?
Who are you, kid?
有坏消息吗?
Is that bad?
我的天啊
Oh, hell.
天啊!
Oh, hell!
- 他们跟着你来的  - 什么? 谁啊?
- They followed you here.  - What? Who?
机器人
Robots.
我从来没见过他们
I've never seen them before.
约翰·弗朗西斯·沃克
John Francis Walker.
因为同意不再干扰 所以你才被允许继续活着
You have been permitted to live based upon your agreed non-intervention.
如今你包庇一名逃犯
You are now harboring a fugitive element.
把她交给我们扣押 否则准备被消灭
Release her to our custody or be extinguished.
你只有1分钟做出选择
You have 1 minute to comply.
- 谢谢  - 先别谢我
- Thanks.  - Don't thank me yet.
嗯!
Huh!
等等
Wait.
快点!
Come on!
当心!
Look out!
快走
Go.
约翰·弗朗西斯·沃克 根据尼克斯总督的授权
John Francis Walker. By authority of Governor Nix.
本机已经获权... 结束你的生命
This unit has been authorized... to extinguish your life...
好了
Okay.
好了 敲够了 打够了
Alright, that's enough. That's enough.
随手关门
Close the door.
尼克斯总督是什么人
Who the hell is Governor Nix?
快走 麻利点
Let's go. Come on.
这个算个鬼办法啊?!
How is this a good idea?!
哇哦!
Whoa!
快点 不然就沉了 小鬼!
Move or sink, kid!
你还真有备无患啊?
You were actually prepared for that?
- 我的帽子  - 别管它了
- My hat.  - Leave it.
不行 不行 我不能丢了它
No no no. I can't go without it.
这是我老爸的
It's my dad's.
太聪明了对你自己不好
You're too smart for your own good.
你老爸无法理解你 不会支持你
Your father never understood you, never supported you.
而你现在带着他的帽子
Now you wear his hat,
不知道是纪念还是叛逆
as a badge or rebellion.
没错吧?
Right?
不是 我老爸可棒了
No. My Dad is amazing.
哦 等等 我们...
Oh. Wait a second. We're not...
我们不是在说我 对吧?
We're not talking about me, are we?
我是要把你送回你了不起的爸爸身边
Well, we just get you to your amazing dad...
假装这一切从没发生过
Pretend this never happened.
坐上来
Hop on.
- 电池没电了  - 不可能
- Battery's dead.  - No, it's not.
- 也许该换了  - 不是的
- Well maybe it's the point. - No, it's not.
- 你上次开...  - 你知道你在帮倒忙吧?
- When's the last time you tried...  - You know you're not helping?
躲起来 快点
Get down. Now.
等等
Wait.
你好 弗兰克
Hello, Frank.
你打算开枪吗?
Are you going to shoot me?
- 我还在考虑...  - 你能进车里考虑吗?
- I'm deciding...  - Could you decide in the truck?
因为我们真的需要快点出发了
Because we really should get going.
等等
Wait.
怎么了 等其他更多机器人来吗?
Why, so more robots can show up?
她算其中一个
She's one of 'em.
我知道的 你到底来不来啊?
Yeah, I know. Are you coming or not?
过去点
Move over.
- 弗兰克?  - 还没想好呢
- Frank?  - Not yet.
你在想什么 你干嘛要把她扯进来?
What were you thinking, why would you drag her into this?
我没把她扯进什么里面
I didn't drag her into anything.
我就给了她一枚勋章 其余是她自己的事
I gave her a pin. She did the rest.
和你一个样
Just like you.
哦 别... 你从哪里找到勋章的?
Oh, don't even... And where did you even find the pin?
我亲眼看到他们毁掉了所有勋章
I was there. They destroyed them.
没有都毁 我还藏着近十个
Not all of them. I made it out with nearly a dozen.
所以你给了一个小年轻?
So you give one to a teenager?
嗨 我可是在什么费恩伯格·杜塞多夫测试里得了73分的
Hey, I got a 73 on the Feinberg- Dusseldorf scale or whatever.
- 你得了73分? 这不可能的事  - 嗯哼
- You got a 73? That's not possible.  - Mm-Hm.
他是妒忌你 因为他只有41分
He's jealous because he scored 41.
什... 你懂什么? 我那时才11岁
Wha... You know what? I was 11.
才11岁
I was 11.
别动它!
Don't touch that!
这是一千吨当量的炸药 不是什么玩具
This is a 1 kiloton detonation, it is not a toy.
别乱动我东西 你听懂吗?
Do not mess with my stuff. You got it?
- 对不起  - 我最开始不是选她的 你知道吗
- Sorry.  - I didn't begin with her, you know.
我花了好几年挑选潜在对象
I wasted years holding out for potential candidates.
潜在对象? 干什么啊?
Potential candidates? For what?
哦吼吼...
Oh-ho-ho...
有意思了 你还认为你
That's beautiful. You still think you're recruiting, don't you?
别再问她更多问题了
Do not ask her any more questions.
不然她分分钟关机给你看
She's gonna do her countermeasure shutdown thing.
防范关机措施?
What countermeasure shutdown?
你告诉她 你有什么防范关机措施?
Did you tell her you had a countermeasure shutdown thing?
- 是她在烦我  - 什么...? 你... 你骗我?
- She was annoying me.  - What...? You... You lied?
早点习惯吧 小鬼
Get used to that, kid.
前一秒 她保证你有个美好的未来
One minute, she's promising you a beautiful future.
下一秒 她就带人来你家消灭你
Next thing you know, she's leading it to your house to kill you.
对不起 但时间不等人 而你需要做事的动力
I'm sorry. But time is running out and you needed motivation.
动力干什么啊?
Motivation for what?
我们需要回去 弗兰克
We need to go back over, Frank.
回去?
Back over there?
好的 好的! 弗兰克 我们需要回去
Yes! Yes! Frank, we need to go back over.
好的! 好极了 这是太好了
Good! Great. That's just great.
老话怎么说的 "嗨 我被蜜蜂咬了 我们直接冲进蜂巢里吧"
You know, "Hey, I got stung by a bee, let's jump on the hive."
这比喻太糟糕了
That's a terrible analogy.
这个比喻再恰当不过! 你懂什么叫比喻吗?
That's a fantastic analogy! What do you know about analogy?
你知道么 你这样子不可能和你好好交流的
You know you're impossible to talk to when you're like this.
我想这个样子 因为你搞砸了我的生活! 现在也是!
I am like this, because you derailed my life! Again!
弗兰克 我不是故意的 都是程序惹的祸
Frank, it's not personal. It's just programming.
我们到了!
We're here!
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
你在这里有个传送站 对吧
This is where your wire station's located, isn't it?
我们要制造精彩表演
We need to get to the Spectacle.
- 精彩表演  - 你疯了吗
- Spectacle?  - Hey. Are you insane?
他们知道你派她来找我 他们早在这里候着我们了
They know that you sent her to me, they're gonna be waiting for us.
好吧 把爱迪生管给我 我们自己去就行
Fine. Give me the Edison tube and we'll go without you.
我没带爱迪生管
I don't have the Edison tube.
就在你包里
It's in your bag.
我自带X光透视功能
I have X-ray vision.
- 你什么时候有透视能力了?  - 哦 她总是出人意料
- When did you get X-ray vision?  - Oh. She's full of surprises.
我了解她的所有特点 其中最主要的一条是
I know all about her surprises. Chief among them is this,
她不在乎你
she doesn't care about you.
所有的吸引力 使命感 可爱的微笑
All that charm and the sense of purpose and the cute little smile.
这都只是软件的作用
It's all just software.
一堆0和1 仅此而已
It's 1s and 0s. That's it.
相信我 等你到了那里 你全得靠自己
Trust me, when you get there, you're on your own.
你们俩怎么了?
What happened to you two?
他觉得我伤害了他
He thinks I hurt him.
不 你伤害的是一个笨蛋 他傻到...
No. You hurt a dumb kid that was stupid enough to fall...
你可以是各种人 弗兰克·沃克
You were many things, Frank Walker.
但绝不是笨蛋
But you were never dumb.
你为什么不直接把爱迪生管给我?
Why don't you just give me the Edison tube?
- 我什么也不会给你  - 还有...
- I'm not giving you anything.  - And...
我...!
I'm...!
好吧
Alright.
你想进? 我就带你进去 有何不可
You want in? I'll bring you in. Why not.
有什么好过在这儿等待 受伤 被杀等等等等
What's better than waiting around here and getting hunted and killed, etc, etc.
- 说到重点了!  - 等等?
- That's the spirit!  - Et cetera?
等等是指什么?
What's the et cetera?
这些是什么电缆?
What kind of cables are these?
传输人的那种
The kind that transmit people.
人 我们吗? 像微型传送机...
People, like us? What, like a miniature teleport...
我一定得解释每件事吗?
Do I have to explain everything?
你不能惊讶完就完了吗?
Can't you just be amazed and move on?
这一切都奇怪得值得挖掘
This is all wired to the dish up there.
你... 你用的是卫星吗?
Are you... Are you using satellite?
我知道那是怎么运作的
I know how things work.
来 给你个惊喜
Well, zip-a-Dee-doo for you.
用这个把你的眼睛包起来 包紧
Wrap this around your eyes, tight.
- 为什么?  - 因为正义是盲目的
- Why?  - Because justice is blind.
你就照做吧 孩子
Just. Do it, kid.
你要我用这个把头缠起来?
You want me to put this over my head?
- 要是这个粘住我眉毛...  - 闭嘴
- If this sticks on my eyebrows...  - Shut up.
张开嘴 头往后仰
Open your mouth, tilt your head back.
啊 那是什么?
Awk. What is that?
粉末 你不进来吗?
Powder. Will ya back off?
可以出发了!
Good to go!
很好 目的地设置为塔了吗?
Good. Did you set it for the tower?
那里还有个接收器
There is still a receiver there.
我上次检查过了
Last I checked.
那是多久前了?
How long ago was that?
25年前
25 years ago.
大概吧
Roughly.
他们也把你赶出去了?
They threw you out too?
好了两位 杀手机器人
Okay guys, killer robots.
好吧 一会儿会很亮 很冷 而且非常吵
Alright. It's gonna be bright, cold, and really loud.
在百分之一秒内 你会失去90%的血糖
You're gonna lose 90% of your blood sugar in 1/100 of a per second
你会希望自己死了
and you're gonna wish you were dead.
到那时候 就结束了
By then, it'll be over.
别尿我们身上
Don't pee on us.
听起来很精彩
This sounds spectacular.
为什么是现在? 为什么是她?
Why now? Why her?
因为她没有放弃
Because she hasn't given up.
你觉得她能修好它
You think she can fix it.
为什么这么说?
What makes you say that?
她可以吗 雅典娜?
Can she, Athena?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我们去寻找答案吧
Let's go find out.
抓紧了
Hold on.
这... 这是正常的吗?
Is this... Is this normal?
发... 生... 什么了?
What... is... happen... ing...?
我好渴 我要死了
I'm thirsty. I'm dying.
我觉得要死了
I think I'm dying.
- 要死了 要死了  - 你不会死的
- I'm dying. I'm dying. - You're not dying.
冰箱里有可乐
There's coke in the fridge.
随便喝
Help yourself.
我们不知道这里有多少人
We have no idea how many are here.
但很肯定的是 他们知道我们来了 所以
But we're damn sure they know we're coming. So.
我们动作要快 你们跟着我 不许提问 明白吗?
We move quickly, you follow me. No questions, got it?
- 明白  - 好
- Got it.  - Alright.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我们在巴黎?
We're in Paris?
你能不要这么惊讶吗?
Would you stop being so amazed?
- 我还以为你希望我惊讶点  - 我希望你别再叫了
- I thought you wanted me to be amazed. - I want you to stop yapping.
塔正在关闭
Tower's closing.
该死
Oh, hell.
过来
Come here.
现在 我们俩会在他们的监视名单里
Now. You and I are gonna be on their watch list.
他们也许还没上传你的面部识别文件
They may not have your facial recognition profile uploaded yet.
- 也许?  - 也许 所以...
- May not?  - May not, so...
你走到那里 拿着这个 敲他的脖子
You walk over there, you take this, you tap him on the neck.
如果他是人类 它会直接敲晕他
If he's human, it knocks him right out.
如果是机器人呢?
And if it's a robot?
- 嘿  - 那你就直接惹怒它了
- Hey. - Then you'll just pissed it off.
好极了
Fantastic.
她有胆量 你得给她机会
She got guts. You gotta give her that.
人类!
Human!
当埃菲尔第一次在巴黎世界博览会上 揭幕这座铁塔时
The French hated this thing when Eiffel first unveiled it
法国人都不喜欢它 觉得它碍眼
at the Paris World's Fair. They thought it was an eyesore.
但埃菲尔并不在意 铁塔的意义不在于成为丰碑
Eiffel didn't care though. It wasn't meant to be a monument.
而在于寻找另一个世界
It was meant to find another world.
第一个传输站
Le cat premiere.
加上四位伟人先驱
Plus Ultra's first four.
他们也参与了这一切?
They were a part of all this?
埃菲尔 儒勒·凡尔纳 特斯拉 以及爱迪生先生
Eiffel, Jules Verne, Tesla, and Mr. Edison.
他们设计了这个天线 而我们正在里面...
They designed this antenna that we're inside...
等等 什么? 埃菲尔铁塔是根天线?
Wait, what? The Eiffel Tower's an antenna?
现在我终于回答你的问题了 你要打断我吗?
Now I finally answer your question. Are you gonna interrupt me?
是的 特斯拉设计了天线来观察外面各种频率
Yes, Tesla designed the antenna to observe every kind of frequency out there.
子空间 维度转换 应有尽有
Subspace, trans-dimensional, you name it.
后来 他们真的找到了他们正在寻找的东西
And, they found exactly what they were looking for.
再后来 爱迪生试图独揽功劳
And then, Edison tried to take credit for it,
- 因为这两个人互相不满...  - 弗兰克
- because these two hate each other they....  - Frank.
别偏题
Stay on topic.
好
Yeah.
当时谣言满地 都是从一个秘密入口传出来的...
There were all these rumors, of a secret entrance...
那是这四个人留给自己的 一张单行票...
the four kept just for themselves, a one way ticket...
以防不测
in case of emergencies.
壮观的场面
The Spectacle.
好戏还在后头 孩子
You ain't seen nothing yet, kid.
哦不 旅行结束了
Oh no. The tour is over.
这是个火箭
It's a rocket.
他们来了
They're coming.
好了
Alright.
扣紧安全带
Buckle up.
- 他说什么?  - 跟你能想到的差不多
- What'd he say?  - Pretty much what you'd expect.
让他们别动
Tell them to hang on.
哇... 吼...!
WOO...  HOO...!
- 我们为什么往回走?  - 我们没有
- Why are we going back?  - We're not.
我们要穿过去 到另一个维度
We're going through. To another dimension.
所以我们冲进外太空 就为了助跑?
So we blasted into outer space just to get a running start?
这个可能有点奇怪
This part may get a little weird.
凯西
Casey.
醒醒
Wake up.
凯西?
Casey?
凯西 醒醒
Casey. Wake up.
我们到了
We're here.
现在怎么办?
Now what?
你告诉我
You tell me.
我告诉你? 这是你的主意
I tell you? This was your idea.
我不知道 我只是找到了知道的人
I don't have ideas. I just find the people who do.
- 所以根本没有计划  - 有一个计划
- So there's no plan.  - There's a plan.
你只是还没想到而已
You just haven't come up with it yet.
但你得快点想
But, you should do that soon.
真是棒极了
That's just terrific.
给 藏起来
Here. Hide this.
必须的
Absolutely.
等等 那是你不让我玩的千吨级爆炸物吗?
Wait, is that the 1 kiloton detonation thingy you told me not to play with?
此时此刻 这是我们的保障品
Right now, it's our insurance policy.
现在他们有个在门口杀我们的好机会
There's a good chance they're gonna try and kill us right at the gate.
我们就站在这儿?
So we're just gonna stand here?
你想看明日世界
Well, you wanted to see Tomorrowland.
这就是了
Here it comes.
拿上包
Take the bag.
- 弗兰克  - 大卫
- Frank.  - David.
你看起来不错啊
You look well.
岁月改变了你
Age becomes you.
谢谢 你也该试试
Thanks. You should try it.
我不知道 我想我会继续每天早上喝我的饮料
I don't know. I think I'll just keep drinking my shake every morning.
现在加巧克力了
Comes in chocolate now.
不错
Yum.
你好 雅典娜
Hello, Athena.
还以为你永远不会回来了
Started to think you were never coming home.
你去哪里了?
Where oh where have you been?
做我的工作
Doing my job.
你的工作?
Your job?
不好意思 我们中止你的招募协议时 说得还不清楚吗?
I'm sorry, were we not clear when we suspended your recruitment protocols?
在你叫我该死的废物 还想拆开我的时候
I got that since when you called me bloody obsolete
我就知道了
and tried to disassemble me.
你从埃菲尔铁塔发射出一个古代的火箭
Well, you certainly caused quite a commotion
一定引起了骚乱吧
by launching an antique rocket ship out of the Eiffel tower!
在正常的情况下
Under normal circumstances,
我们要花额外的时间来说服每个人相信那只是场特效表演...
we'd be working overtime to convince everyone it was just an elaborate hoax...
可惜 对我们来说 现在这并不重要 对吗?
Unfortunately, for all of us, it doesn't really matter now, does it?
为什么不重要?
Why doesn't it matter?
你又是谁?
And who might you be?
我... 我是凯西·纽顿
I'm... I'm Casey Newton.
你呢... 你又是谁?
And who... who might you be?
大卫·尼克斯 幸会
David Nix. Pleasure.
弗兰克 很高兴能碰上面
Well, Frank, it's been wonderful catching up.
但我们都知道 你被流放
But as we were fairly clear about the terms of your exile,
以及反抗的结果
and the consequences of violating it,
我不得不问
I have to ask.
你到底来这儿干嘛?
What the hell are you doing here?
我觉得她能修好它
I think she can fix it.
抱歉 我...
I'm sorry, I...
她 我觉得她能修好它 大卫
Her. I think she can fix it, David.
等等 什么?
Wait, what?
我一直在捕捉你的信号 每次你在这里开启
I've been pirating your signal. Every time you turn it on here,
我都可以在那边看到
I can see it there.
它闪了 百分比下降了 大卫
And it flickered. The percentage dropped, David.
不可能
Impossible.
你不相信我 我们去看看 就现在
You don't believe me, let's go find out, right now.
不好意思 我能修好什么?
I'm sorry, what can I fix?
世界 纽顿小姐 他觉得你能修好世界
The world, Ms. Newton. He thinks you can fix the world.
就像一个通往地球的传送门?
Is that like a portal to Earth?
不 这是通往地球的桥梁
No. It is a bridge way to Earth.
欢迎回到监测中心 弗兰克
Welcome back to The Monitor, Frank.
这东西真伟大 对吗?
It's something, isn't it?
的确
Yeah, it's something.
不用担心灯光
Don't worry about the light show.
这是绝对安全的
It's perfectly safe.
- 我要做什么吗?  - 不用
- Am I supposed to do something?  - No.
好吧 你能再具体点吗 因为修好世界听起来有点...
Okay, can you be a bit more specific because fixing the world sounds a little...
做你自己就好
Just be yourself.
明白
Gotcha.
那些是什么?
What are those?
未来的闪影
Flashes of future.
那是从现在起的几秒钟
That's a few seconds from now.
这整座塔如漏斗般放出速子的能量
This whole tower funnels energy by tachyon.
一种移动速度比光还快的粒子
A particle that moves significantly faster than light.
大约四十年前 我们就发现了它们
We discovered them almost forty years ago.
你们的物理学家还在讨论它们是否存在
Your physicists are still arguing over whether they exist.
天啊 太晚了
Oh, dear. Too late.
那么 好戏上演
So. On with the show.
我们已经突破性地改善了接口
We've enhanced the interface significantly.
你们的原始算法仍在起作用
There's still functions on your original algorithm.
你有东西给我看 弗兰克?
You have something to show me, Frank?
给我看
Show me.
挑个地方
Pick a place.
- 什么?  - 一个地方 世界上的任何地方
- What?  - A location. Anywhere in the world.
挑一个
Pick one.
卡那维拉尔 卡那维拉尔角
Canaveral, Cape Canaveral.
小意思
Easy.
这个接口是从你的手 指向地球的中心
The Interface is oriented from your hands to the center of the Earth.
好的 明白
Okay, I got it.
你显然训练过她了
You've trained her, obviously.
我昨天才遇见她
I just met her yesterday.
她知道运作的原理
She knows how things work.
这怎么可能?
How is this possible?
我们身处的地方 离你这个家
We are millions of exponential deviances
距离成级数般地遥远
away from the dimension you call home.
弗兰克有了一个崇高的想法 制造出了这个机器
Frank had the noble idea of building this machine so that we could
能让我们保持联系
keep in touch.
这是三天前
This is 3 days ago.
相对的
Relatively.
那是时空连续的
That's space-time humor.
因为速子的速度比光还快
Because tachyons travel faster than light,
一旦我们控制了它们...
once we harness them...
你可以看到时光倒流
You can see backwards in time.
不只是过去
Not just backwards.
你在开玩笑
You're kidding.
不
No.
怎么回事?
What happened?
继续
Keep going.
再远一点
Just a little further.
够了
That's enough.
够了 孩子
That's enough, kid.
那是我家
That's my house.
要是弗兰克让你做好了准备 那就好了
Would have been nice, if Frank had prepared you for this.
恐怕 世界要终结了
I'm afraid the world is ending.
这是一定的 不可避免的 它正在到来
It is certain, it is unavoidable, and it is coming.
什么时候?
When?
现在起的58天
This is 58 days from now.
58天?
58 days?
不论是什么造成的 静态开始后 随时都会发生
Whatever caused this, could happen anytime after the static starts.
可能是一个月 甚至更早
It could be a month, could be sooner.
还在找你的闪影吗 弗兰克?
Still looking for your flicker, Frank?
我知道自己看见了什么
I know what I saw.
那你为什么没告诉任何人?
So why aren't you telling anyone?
整个星球就要灭亡了 而你就坐在这儿?
The whole planet is gonna die, and you're just, sitting here?
我们不会死的
We're not gonna die.
那是你的世界 不是我们的
This is your world, not ours.
我们在这里会安然无恙
We'll be perfectly fine here.
那你为什么不让大家都进来?
Then why don't you let people in?
- 告诉她 大卫  - 哦 弗兰克
- Tell her, David.  - Oh, Frank.
流放了那么些年 你还是不明白
All those years in exile and you still don't understand.
这些人是... 他们是受野蛮驱使的
These people are... They're driven by savagery.
如果我们告诉了他们这个地方
If we told them about this place,
同样的事情会发生在这里 发生在我们身上
then that, would happen here, to us.
到时 谁也活不下来
Then nothing would survive.
但那还没有发生
But it hasn't happened yet.
事实上 它已经发生了 你只是还没接受而已
Actually it has happened. You just haven't accepted it.
我不接受
Well I don't accept it.
你看见了吗? 你刚刚看见了吗?
You see that? Did you see that?
大卫 我知道你看到了 那意味着还有机会
David, I know that you saw that. That means that there is a chance.
至少还有机会
There's at least a chance.
进展很顺利 对吧?
That went quite well, don't you think?
发生了什么事情?
What happened?
你被驱逐了...
You're being deported...
又一次
again.
那就是尼克斯
Well, that's Nix for you.
毫无创新精神
No new ideas.
很明显你那在不可避免性中万分之一的几率
Apparently your 1/10.000 furball in the inevitability
不够有说服力让他改变主意
wasn't convincing enough to change his mind.
温柔点
Be gentle.
没事吧?
You okay?
我知道你认为我之前问你的无数问题时
I know you think somewhere in the zillions of questions that I was asking you,
你本可以回答 " 哦 凯西 那问题其实无关紧要
you could've said, "Oh, Casey. Well that's stuff not really the issue
因为我们的未来预测机显示我们都要死了 "
because our future predicting machine says we're all gonna die."
他的确有暗示过
He did sort of hinted at it.
这地方一点希望也没有
This place has nothing to do with hope.
- 完全就是绝望  - 别这样 别那样说
- It's the opposite of hope.  - Come on, don't say that.
为什么? 你也说过了
Why not? You said it.
难怪你放弃了
No wonder you gave up.
那是在认识你之前
That's before I knew about you.
你真的...
You really...
你真的很特别
You really are special.
为什么你们这些人一直和我说那个?
Why do you people keep saying that to me?
我不特别
I'm not.
你给我这个干嘛? 哼
Why'd you even give me this? Hm.
你向我展示了一个神奇美妙的地方 但一切都是假的
You showed me a place, that was amazing and incredible, and it was a lie.
如果你打算把想法植入别人的头脑
If you're gonna zap an idea into people's heads,
你就应该确保那是真的
you should really make sure that it's the truth.
因为你不能这么做 你不能植入...
Because you can't do that. You can't just zap...
什么?
What?
你把想法植入别人的头脑
You zap an idea into people's heads.
你之前盗用了信号 你是怎么做到的?
You were pirating the signal. How?
- 什么?  - 在你家
- What?  - At your house,
有间房的电视机里 都播放着末日图像
all your TVs, your doomsday room.
你从接收到了监测仪发出的信号
You were boosting the feed from that Monitor thing.
- 你怎么做到的?  - 很简单
- How did you do that?  - No big deal.
它的信号太强了 随便一个蹩脚的收音机都可以接受信号
They're running so much power through it now, a ham radio can pick it up.
只是要找对合适的频率
It's just a matter of finding the right frequency.
你捕捉到了这个空间里的信号
You grabbed a signal from another dimension.
信号来自这个空间的监测仪 也就是说它在往我们的世界发信号
From a machine here. That means it's transmitting there.
也许监测仪不只是在预测未来
What if it's not just predicting the future.
也在传播信息
He's broadcasting it.
刚才我接触了这机器几分钟
When I touched this thing, for a few minutes,
我感觉任何事情都是可能的
it felt like anything was possible.
那为什么没出现好的预测?
So then why can't the opposite happen?
如果那个监测仪只是一个巨型接收器
What if The Monitor is just a giant pin,
但它不是让你积极地思考 而是让你消极地思考 它...
but instead of making you think positive, it makes you think negative. And it...
它在...
And it's...
说服全世界去喂错误的狼
convincing the whole world to feed the wrong wolf.
我们要把那东西关了
We need to turn that thing off.
是时候回家了
It's time to go home.
大卫 大卫
David. David.
- 啊! 这地方没人住 地图上也没标明  - 听我说
- Ah! It's uninhabited and uncharted.  - Listen to me.
看上去是你们度过余生的好地方
But it looks like a lovely place to spend your last days.
大卫 监测仪现在像是天线
David, The Monitor is acting as an antenna.
它不仅仅是在接收超光子
It isn't just receiving tachyons,
它还选择了其中一种可能性 让我们去相信...
it is taking a possible future and making it like...
它夸大其词 传播末日景象 反复灌输给我们
Amplifying it, transmitting it, like a feedback loop.
这是一个主观意识的预言 就是监测仪发出的
It's a self-fulfilling prophecy that is coming from right there.
但它并不仅向人们展示世界末日的景象
But it's not just showing people the end of the world.
它还反复给人们灌输这个想法
It's giving them the idea over and over
- 直到人们相信末日真的会发生  - 这是一颗滴答作响的定时炸弹
- and over again until they just accept it.  - It's a ticking time bomb.
而我们就是点燃导火索的人
And we're the ones that lit the fuse.
我们还有58天来尝试和改变
We still have 58 days to try and change things,
但是只要那东西还在运作 就无法成功
but nothing will work as long as that thing is still on.
小女孩 我认为你的超光子融合的理论有一点不完整
Young lady, I'm gonna assume that your knowledge of tachyonic fusion is a little sketchy.
不可能关了它
Shutting it down is impossible.
没有"关"这个健
There is no 'Off'.
我告诉你它在做什么 为什么你不在乎?
I'm telling you what it's doing. Why don't you care?
因为正是他在操作
Because he's the one that's doing it.
对吗?
Right?
我们设想下
Let's imagine
如果你瞥见未来
If you glimpse the future,
被你看到的场景吓坏了 你会如何应对?
and were frightened by what you saw, what would you do with that information?
你会去找政客吗?
Would you go to politicians?
大企业的首脑? 你如何说服他们?
Captains of industry? And how would you convince them?
用数据和事实吗?
With data, facts?
那祝你好运
Good luck.
他们唯一不会做的事
The only facts they won't challenge,
是让经济运转
are the ones that keep the wheels greased,
钱财滚滚来的事实
and the dollars rolling in.
但是如果有办法跳过中间人
But what if there was a way of skipping the middle man,
直接把重要消息植入每个人的头脑
and putting the critical news directly into everyone's head.
大幅度灭绝的可能性会一直上升
The probability of widespread annihilation kept going up.
唯一让它停止的方式 就是把它展示出来
The only way to stop it, was to show it.
直接让人们吓个半死
To scare people straight.
理智的人类怎么不会被一切事物的毁灭所惊醒
What reasonable human being wouldn't be galvanized
那一切我们熟知而深爱的事物
by the potential destruction of everything we've ever known or loved.
为了拯救文明
To save civilization,
我要展示它的坍塌
I would show its collapse.
但是你觉得人们是怎么对待这个预测?
But how do you think this vision was received?
你认为人们是怎样回应
How do you think people responded
即将发生的末日景象?
to the prospect of imminent doom?
他们把它吞了 就像吃巧克力泡芙一样
They gobbled it up, like a chocolate eclair.
他们不害怕死亡 他们把它重新打包
They didn't fear their demise, they repackaged it.
把它当做视频游戏 电视节目 书籍和电影一样来消遣
It can be enjoyed as video games, as TV shows, books, movies.
全世界全身心地接受世界末日
The entire world wholeheartedly embraced the apocalypse,
带着欢乐的抛弃精神朝着世界末日冲刺
and sprinted towards it with gleeful abandon.
同时 在你们周围 地球在崩塌
Meanwhile, your earth was crumbling all around you.
你们地球人肥胖和饥饿同时泛滥
You got simultaneous epidemics of obesity and starvation.
解释一下吧
Explain that one.
蜜蜂和蝴蝶开始消失
Bees and butterflies start to disappear.
冰川消融
The glaciers melt.
藻类滋蔓
Algae blooms.
全在你们周围 煤矿的金丝雀暴死
All around you. The coal mine canaries are dropping dead,
你们也不领会暗示!
and you won't take the hint!
每一刻 都有机会创造一个更好的未来
In every moment, there is the possibility of a better future.
但是你们人类不相信
But you people won't believe it.
因为你们不愿意相信
And because you won't believe it,
你们就不会采取行动 实现更好的未来
you wouldn't do what is necessary to make it a reality.
你们老是认为未来是可怕的
So you dwell on this so terrible future.
你们屈从于这个想法 因为一个理由
You resign yourselves to it. For one reason.
因为未来没向今天的你们索取过任何东西
Because that future doesn't ask anything of you today.
没错 你们看到了冰川 警告了泰坦尼克号
So. Yes, you saw the iceberg, you warned the Titanic.
但你们仍然驶向冰川 全速前进
but you all just steered for it anyway. Full steam ahead.
为什么?
Why?
因为你们想下沉
Because you want to sink.
你们放弃了
You gave up.
那可不是监测仪的错
That's not The Monitor's fault.
而是你们人类
That's yours.
把他们带过去
Put them through.
感谢来访 弗兰克
Thanks for visiting, Frank.
再次见到你真的很高兴
It's genuinely nice to see you again.
- 你在做什么?  - 不放弃
- What are you doing?  - Not giving up.
小心!
Look out!
- 拿那东西!  - 什么东西?
- Get the thing!  - What thing?
我们刚来这里时我给你的东西
The thing I gave you when we first got here.
引爆它! 跳上平台!
Arm it! Get on the platform!
凯西 炸弹!
Casey, the bomb!
去平台上面!
Get on the platform!
- 现在呢?  - 引爆它!
- Now what?  - Arm it!
怎么引爆?
How?
凯西!
Casey!
炸弹? 炸弹在哪里?
The bomb? Where's the bomb?
一分钟后爆炸
1 minute to detonation.
- 45秒  - 雅典娜!
- 45 seconds.  - Athena!
炸弹 我要怎么做? 我怎么关掉它?
Bomb. What do I do? How do I turn it off?
30秒
30 seconds.
你关不了
You can't.
哈 哈 哈...
Ha-ha-ha...
这一点也不好笑
This is not funny.
弗兰克 快走开! 要炸了!
Frank, get out of there! It's gonna blow!
走开...!
Get out...!
离开那里!
Get out of there!
- 关上传送门!
- Close the portal!
- 你没事吧?  - 炸弹没了
- Are you alright?  - The bomb is gone.
- 站得起来吗?  - 可以
- Can you stand?  - Yeah.
弗兰克!
Frank!
不要
No.
- 发生了什么? 她还好吗?  - 我要带她去重修
- What happened? Is she okay? - I need to get her to a repair module.
弗兰克!
Frank!
没人能重修我
No one's going to repair me.
我时间不多了
I'm out of time.
现在我要告诉你一些事情
I need to tell you something now.
我完了
I'm done.
我要停止运转了
I'm shutting down.
我要...
I'm...
停止运转了
shutting down.
我信号要没了
I'm going to lose sync.
别这样看着我
Don't look at me like that.
我终于觉得这不是...
I finally think it's not...
失败
failure.
我知道
I know.
我死前需要告诉你一些事情
There are things I need to tell you before the final
在自动程序侵入前
Before the automative program kicks in.
我是一台机器
I'm a machine.
直到我看到你发现我是机器时你的脸色
I never thought that was bad
我才觉得作为机器人并不好
until I see your face when you found out I was.
我一直都知道
I always knew.
不 你不知道
No, you didn't.
系统失败 激活最后的思想
Systems failing. Activating last thoughts,
为弗兰克·沃克而储存
saved for Frank Walker.
1 1965年9月
Log 15. September 1965.
弗兰克·沃克以一种难以识别的方式看着我
Frank Walker is looking at me in a manner that is difficult to recognize.
似乎我必须要和他解释我是一个音频电子人
It seems imperative to explain to him that I'm an Audio Animatronic.
雅典娜
Athena.
但是我害怕当他发现我不是人类时
But I'm concerned that he may be adversely affected,
会对他产生不利影响
when he finds out that I'm not human.
他有潜力 我不想破坏它
He has potential. I don't want to damage it.
他需要人相信他
He needs someone to believe in him.
我刚好满足了那个需要
And I'm fulfilling that need.
他是我最好的新人
He's my top recruit.
2 1965年10月
Log 24. October 1965.
我对弗兰克·沃克有了不寻常的想法
I'm having unusual thoughts towards Frank Walker.
我怀疑我的情感接口出了点问题
I suspect a flaw in my empathy interface.
我觉得我应该要报告
I'm thinking I should report it.
但是我没有
But I haven't.
我也无法解释原因
I cannot explain why.
3 1984年4月
Log 78. April 1984.
弗兰克·沃克被尼克斯总督放逐了
Frank Walker has been banished by Governor Nix.
他说他已经失去希望了
He says he's lost hope.
他责怪我一开始给他希望
And he holds me responsible for having given it to him in the first place.
我不明白
I do not understand this.
他说我永远不会明白
He says I never will.
因为我感觉不到生气 失望
Because I do not feel anger, or disappointment
或是爱情
or love.
结束录音
End recording.
我的任务是寻找追梦者
I was designed to find dreamers.
我找到了你
I found you.
我失去了你
I lost you.
直到我找到了她
Until I found her.
凯西
Casey.
追梦者需要在一起
Dreamers need to stick together.
这话不是程序里写的
It's not programming.
是我个人想对你说的
It's personal.
监测仪 炸弹没了
The Monitor. The bomb is gone.
但我还没...
But I'm not.... yet.
时间不多了
There isn't much time.
我的自毁程序 使用它
My self-destruct. Use it.
你知道怎么做 弗兰克
You know what to do, Frank.
这一次你知道怎样做才是对的
How to get this right, this time.
我认为你没有想法.
I thought you can't have ideas.
好吧 你知道什么?
W-Well. W-What do you know?
你知道什么?
What do you know?
系统失败
Systems failing.
- 弗兰克  - 嗯
- Frank.  - Yeah.
你 你知道为什么你没法让我笑吗?
Do-Do you want to know why you couldn't have make me laugh?
为什么?
Why?
因为你一点都不搞笑
Because you're not funny.
你可以放手了
You can let me go now.
再见 弗兰克
Goodbye, Frank.
再见 雅典娜
Goodbye, Athena.
哦 扯淡
Oh, bollocks.
现在该干嘛?
Now, what?
你问我?
You're asking me?
这是你的主意 孩子
This was your idea, kid.
是啊
Yeah.
你觉得能行吗?
You think it'll work?
我想我们必须让它成功
I guess we have to make it work.
因此我们让它成功了
So, we're making it work.
首先
First order of business.
把门重新打开
Get the door back open.
吸收些有经验的工程师也不错
Couldn't hurt to get a few experienced engineers over here.
- 下一步呢?  - 重新开派对
- Next?  - Put the party back on.
打印些新的邀请函
And print out some new invitations.
这就是为什么今天我们会在这里
Which brings us to why we're here today.
一年前本来都玩完了
A year ago it was all supposed to be over.
我们甚至无法出现在这里
We shouldn't even be here.
然而我们做到了
But we are.
监测仪告诉人们世界末日到了
It isn't hard to knock down a big, evil building
摧毁这样一个巨型邪恶的建筑并不难
that's telling everybody that the world's gonna end.
困难的是...
What is hard...
想清楚在它的位置上要建什么东西
Is figuring out what to build in it's place.
如果要完成这个任务
If we're gonna do that,
单干是不行的
we can't do it alone.
我们需要你们所有人
We'll need all of you.
弗兰克·沃克 能问个问题吗?
Frank Walker. May I ask a question?
- 当然  - 你给我们的搜寻参数
- Sure.  - The search parameters you've given us,
虽然是很数字化 但是有点...
while mathematically sound, are a bit...
不明确
undefined.
你能具体点吗?
Could you be more specific, please?
好吧 纽顿小姐?
Well, Miss Newton?
你想告诉新人他们要找什么吗?
You wanna tell our new recruiters what they're looking for?
追梦人
Dreamers.
我们在寻找
We are looking,
追梦人
for dreamers.
任何能喂对狼的人
Anyone who will feed the right wolf.
那么
So.
我曾经告诉你们的祖先
I once told your predecessor
她除了1和0的结合体以外一无是处
that she was nothing but a combination of 1s and 0s.
我错了
I was wrong.
她不仅仅是那样
She was much more than that.
你们也不仅仅是那样
You are much more than that, too.
因此
So.
到那里 完成她要做的事情
Go out there and do what she would have done.
寻找那些没放弃的人
Find the ones who haven't given up.
他们就是未来
They're the future.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 初见 爱喝牛奶 RK翔 Morning 晓笛
校对: 你们茶前辈